Jordan Lefler

801-499-7040 • lefler24@aol.com • linkedin.com/in/jordan-lefler • https://jlefler24.github.io/

Summary:

Result and action-oriented Software Development Professional with extensible experience with software development platforms, and business management. Possesses an in-depth understanding of IT infrastructure, network orientations, and familiarity with a variety of programming languages and concepts.

Technical Skills:

Programming/Development: C# | Python | JavaScript/jQuery | HTML/CSS | Bootstrap | Tkinter

Frameworks/Libraries: ASP.NET | Django | MVC | Entity Framework | React.js

Databases: SQL | MySQL | SQL Server Project Management: Agile | Scrum | DevOps

Version Control: Git & GitHub

IDEs: Visual Studio | VS Code | PyCham

Other Skills: Salesforce | Networking | Troubleshooting

Professional Experience:

Advanced Waste October 2012 – Present

Office Manager/Technical Support:

Tasked with many different roles, from office management, technical support, head of customer relations, Salesforce administration, business finances, payroll and employee training.

Responsibilities/Duties:

- Management of office employees.
- Provide technical support.
- Interacting and building relationships with clients.
- Installation, maintenance, and troubleshooting of computer hardware and software.
- Configured Salesforce Profiles and Administrative permissions to grant/deny users access to platform features.
- Implemented pick lists, field dependencies, lookups, validation and formula fields to the custom objects.
- Created Customized dashboards for team members.

The Tech Academy

June 2020 - August 2020

Software Developer Internship:

For a 2 week sprint, utilized C#, MVC, Entity Framework, MySQL, JavaScript, jQuery, CSS, on a website was meant to be a content management service for managing the content and productions for a theater/acting company with Agile/Scrum methodologies and employed Git and GitHub for version control.

For another 2 week sprint utilized Python, Django, JavaScript, jQuery, CSS, Bootstrap, and SQLite to develop an application to manage and store a user's workout and weightlifting log with full CRUD functionality.

Lexington Law Firm

August 2011 - October 2012

Customer Service Paralegal:

Responsibilities/Duties:

- Assisted clients in repairing there credit
- Answered questions regarding credit, credit reports, and how to repair their credit
- Engaged in a positive/ productive team work environment

Special Projects/Programming Experience:

C# ASP.NET MVC:

• Developed an MVC Web application that simulates a company's algorithm for giving quotes on car insurance. Developed a console app for the classic betting game Blackjack.

Python/Django:

• Developed a Hotel website CRUD application using the Django framework that managed the food menu/room service provided at the Hotel. Other applications include a personal phone book with ADD, EDIT, DELETE in a GUI using Tkinter. A file transfer utility which logged last transfer in SQLITE3 and allowed the user to transfer all created and modified files into selected directories from the past 24 hours.

JavaScript/HTML/CSS:

• Developed github portfolio website. Developed a Pizza Application that accepts user input to customize your pizza order. It then calculates a running total that displays the itemized order and price for the customer.

MS SQL:

• Developed relational database for library management system cataloguing books, authors, publishers, borrowers, branches and branch inventory.

Advanced Waste:

• Helped oversee, manage, and implement a complete change of our business model. Were able to streamline tasks, update computer hardware and software, improve customer relations, and become more efficient. Doubled revenue within a year and have increased each year.

Education:

The Tech Academy | 2020

• Software Developer Boot Camp Certificate - The Tech Academy an immersive boot camp with more than 800 hours of instruction and hands-on training in: C#, ASP.NET, Python, JavaScript, SQL, HTML, CSS, Agile, Scrum, Version Control, and fundamentals of Computer science.

Everest College and Post University | 2011-2013

• Relevant Courses – Programming Fundamentals, College Algebra, Statistics 1 & 2, Hardware and Network Fundamentals

References Available upon request